travelrepublic.co.uk 2010-04-20

# TravelRepublic Privacy Policy

Travel Republic Takes Your Privacy Seriously

## Personal information

Any personal information you provide to us including and similar to your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of Travel Republic Limited Ltd. Except where required by us to process your booking and to ensure that your travel arrangements run smoothly and meet your requirements we need to use the information you provide such as name, address, any special needs/dietary requirements etc. 

We take full responsibility for ensuring that proper security measures are in place to protect your information. We must pass the information on to the relevant suppliers of your travel arrangements such as your tour operator, airlines, hotels, transport companies etc. The information may also be provided to security or credit checking companies, public authorities such as customs/immigration if required by them, or as required by law. 

Additionally, where your holiday is outside the European Economic Area (EEA), controls on data protection in your destination may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country. We will not however, pass any information onto any person not responsible for part of your travel arrangements. This applies to any sensitive information that you give to us such as details of any disabilities, or dietary/religious requirements. (If we cannot pass this information to the relevant suppliers, whether in the EEA or not, we cannot provide your booking. In making this booking, you consent to this information being passed on to the relevant persons.) 

Usually your tour operator or other principal will pass this information onto their suppliers once we have provided it to them. The tour operator or other principal's use of your information is subject to their policy, both in respect of your booking and any future marketing, and is their responsibility. Please ask either us or them for a copy of this if you would like to see it. 

## Credit & Debit Card Details 

All credit card information and personal information is encrypted as it is passed between your browser and our web site. When you make a booking your initial payment is cleared using the information you provide. Your credit card number is not held in our database. All encryption is performed using at least 128 bits making it virtually impossible to decrypt without the necessary decryption key.

### External Sites 

Travel Republic Ltd is not responsible for the content of external internet sites. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.

###  Cookies

A "cookie" is a small data text file that is placed in your browser and allows Travel Republic Ltd to recognize you each time you visit this site (customisation etc). Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, and Travel Republic Ltd does not use cookies to collect personal information. Cookies may also be used to pass information between web sites owned by Travel Republic Ltd.
